{
    "id": "bd0ae79cf2c44d018eab39b811349005",
    "title": "Prepositions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "There are many villages ................... the border.",
            "description": "Across and over can both mean on or to the other side of a road, river or bridge. ",
            "answers": [
                "across",
                "over",
                "on",
                "through"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "......................... thousand people participated in the program.",
            "description": "Over can mean 'more than'. ",
            "answers": [
                "Over",
                "Above",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The boy jumped ...................... the stream.",
            "description": "Across and over can both mean on or to the other side of a road, river or bridge. ",
            "answers": [
                "across",
                "over",
                "along",
                "through"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She was silent all ........................ the journey.",
            "description": "We use through to talk about periods or activities. ",
            "answers": [
                "over",
                "through",
                "across"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Could you pass these leaflets .....................?",
            "description": "Round can be used to talk about distribution. ",
            "answers": [
                "about",
                "round",
                "across",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "'Where is John?' 'He must be somewhere .........................'",
            "description": "Around and about can both be used to indicate indefinite movement and position. ",
            "answers": [
                "around",
                "about",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He spends much of his time doing odd jobs ....................... the house.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "around",
                "about",
                "in",
                "at"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "There were ......................... twenty people at the lecture.",
            "description": "Under can mean less than",
            "answers": [
                "below",
                "under",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "There is something ........................ the bed.",
            "description": "Underneath can be used instead of under to refer to physical position. ",
            "answers": [
                "under",
                "underneath",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The house is too small. ........................... it requires a lot of repairs.",
            "description": "Besides means in addition to.",
            "answers": [
                "Beside",
                "Besides",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I like all musical instruments ...................... the piano.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "except",
                "besides",
                "expect"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He shared the food ........................ his wife, son and daughter.",
            "description": "Before a series of singular nouns, we use share between. ",
            "answers": [
                "between",
                "among",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}